<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rohan Chadha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rohan Chadha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 23:56:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network Effects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 23:56:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-network-effects&#34;&gt;What Are Network Effects?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network effects happen when a product, service, or platform&amp;rsquo;s value increases as more people use it.
The concept shapes business strategy and pricing. This is especially true for products and platforms where user numbers influence value.
Examples of network effects appear in e-commerce (Amazon, Flipkart), ridesharing (Rapido, Uber), delivery platforms (Swiggy, zomato, Zepto), and social media (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-network-effects&#34;&gt;Types of Network Effects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct (Same Side network effect):&lt;/strong&gt; Platform value grows directly as more users join. Examples include social networks like Reddit, Instagram, and LinkedIn.
&lt;strong&gt;Indirect (Cross-Side network effect):&lt;/strong&gt; Value increases for one user group as another group grows. For example, more sellers attract more buyers in e-commerce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frameworks &amp; Principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:35:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/frameworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some good reads on general frameworks and fundas on life, career, teams &amp;amp; Product Management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alexw.substack.com/p/optimism-shapes-reality&#34;&gt;Optimism Shapes Reality&lt;/a&gt; by Scale AI CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a16z.com/16-ways-to-measure-network-effects/&#34;&gt;16 ways to measure Network Effects&lt;/a&gt; - a16z blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Messy Data with 5 minute Gemini Prompt #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/beautifulsoup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:20:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/beautifulsoup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-task&#34;&gt;The Task&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to run a text cleaning operation on almost 500,000 rows of data. The text contained URLs, HTML tags, Math ML tags, and hrefs. I had to clean all of this data before running a pipeline operation on it. I decided to use Gemini to write some starter python code that I could change to get this done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prompt&#34;&gt;The Prompt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent about five minutes writing an initial prompt. I included these points in the prompt:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
